iatn.net 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy - iATN

## dated Aug.14, 2018

### Introduction

Welcome to the privacy notice of **International Automotive Technicians' Network, Inc.** (referred to as "iATN", “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice). 

IATN respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) or as a member of our service and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you. In short: 

  * We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties.
  * We do not share your personal information with advertisers or sponsors.
  * We have zero tolerance for unsolicited commercial email.
  * We encrypt credit card information and secure your personal data.
  * We display member names, company, position, and city, state, country and zipcode in our public member directory, and possibly other areas of our site, including areas showing who is "online" on our network and in Interactive Content created by a member. 
  * We may display the company name, phone number and street address of a business premium member on their iATN web page if the company has indicated that they do business with the general public. This information can be turned off through the Account Settings. 
  * Any Interactive Content posted to or sent through the network, such as through forum posts, is not considered personal data.
  * You may cancel your membership at any time if you do not wish your information to be listed in our public member directory.

More information is provided below in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas.

  1. Important Information and Who We Are
  2. The Data We Collect About You
  3. How is Your Personal Data Collected
  4. How We Use Your Personal Data
  5. Disclosures of Your Personal Data
  6. International Transfers
  7. Data Security
  8. Data Retention
  9. Your Legal Rights
  10. Other Service Information

### 1\. Important Information and Who We Are

#### Purpose of this Privacy Notice.

This privacy notice provides information on how IATN collects and processes personal data through use of this website, including any data you may provide when you sign up as a member. 

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them. 

#### Controller.

IATN is the controller and responsible for your personal data. We have appointed a data privacy champion who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below. 

International Automotive Technicians' Network, Inc.  
Data privacy champion: Marco Iriarte who can be reached at [privacy@solera.com](mailto:privacy@solera.com)  
1301 Solana Blvd., Suite 2100, Westlake, TX 76262 USA  
817-961-2700  

If you are located in Europe, you may have a right to make a complaint at any time to agency for data protection in your country. We would, however, appreciate the opportunity to address any concerns first. 

#### Changes To The Privacy Notice And Your Duty To Inform Us Of Changes.

This privacy notice may be updated by us from time to time. Please keep any contact information current during your relationship with us. 

#### Third-Party Links.

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit. 

#### Information From Children.

This website is not intended for children under the age of sixteen (16) years. Students aged sixteen (16) years and older may register for a READ-ONLY membership under their automotive instructor who is a member. We collect the same types of information from eligible student members as from other members but students may not post Interactive Content or post in forums. 

### 2\. The Data We Collect About You

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you. Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data). We have grouped the types of personal data as follows: 

  1. **Identity Data** includes information such as name, username or identifier, title, date of birth and gender.
  2. **Contact Data** includes information such as addresses, email address and telephone numbers.
  3. **Financial Data** includes information such as bank account and payment card details.
  4. **Transaction Data** includes information such as details about payments and membership and services you have purchased from us.
  5. **Technical Data** includes information such as internet protocol (IP) address, login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website. 
  6. **Profile Data** includes information such as your username and password your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
  7. **Usage Data** includes information such as how you use our website, products and services.
  8. **Marketing and Communications Data** include information such as your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences. 

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice. 

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences. 

#### If You Fail To Provide Personal Data.

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with services). You may also not be able to take advantage of some membership features. 

### 3\. How is your Personal Data Collected?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact, Financial, Profile, and Marketing and Communications Data among others by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you: 
    * apply for, inquire about, or subscribe to membership or other services;
    * create an account on our website;
    * subscribe to publications;
    * request marketing to be sent to you;
    * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
    * give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical, Usage, and Profile Data among others about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We may collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical, Usage, and Profile Data among others about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. We use two types of cookies on our website: Application cookies that are required to make the service function and Tracking cookies from Google, Facebook and Twitter that are not able to be disabled by users. 
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We do not actively collect personal information from outside sources.

### 4\. How We Use Your Personal Data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances: 

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. 
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us. 

#### Purposes For Which We Will Use Your Personal Data.

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate. Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been indicated.  Purpose/Activity | Type of data | Lawful basis for processing  
---|---|---  
To register you as a member | 

  1. Identity 
  2. Contact

|  Performance of a contract with you   
To process and deliver your order and/or provide services to you including: 

  1. Manage payments, fees and charges
  2. Collect and recover money owed to us

NOTE: We currently use Stripe for credit card processing. Stripe has committed to SSL 128-bit security to protect your information while in transit with their servers.  | 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact
  3. Financial
  4. Transaction
  5. Marketing and Communications

| 

  1. Performance of a contract with you
  2. Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)

To display Interactive Content | 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact

| Performance of a contract wth you  
To provide the TechHelp service

NOTE: Your response to another member’s TechHelp request is stored in our database 

| 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact

| Performance of a contract wth you  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

  1. Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
  2. Asking you to leave a review or take a survey
  3. Responding to network messages

| 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact
  3. Profile
  4. Marketing and Communications

| 

  1. Performance of a contract with you
  2. Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
  3. Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)

To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey | 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact
  3. Profile
  4. Usage
  5. Marketing and Communications

| 

  1. Performance of a contract with you
  2. Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)

To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  | 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact
  3. Technical

| 

  1. Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 
  2. Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you  | 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact
  3. Profile
  4. Usage
  5. Marketing and Communications
  6. Technical

|  Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | 

  1. Technical
  2. Usage

|  Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | 

  1. Identity
  2. Contact
  3. Technical
  4. Usage
  5. Profile

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
For the purpose of this notice,

  * **Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you and the market place the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us. 
  * **Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract. 
  * **Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to. 
  * **Interactive Content** means any information contributed by members for use of other members or posted in a communication service of the network such as forums and chat rooms. The following information may be displayed with Interactive Content: name, company, position, city, state, country, zipcode. 

#### Promotional Offers From Us.

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing. 

#### Third-Party Marketing.

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the Solera group of companies for marketing purposes 

#### Opting Out.

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us or changing the settings on your account. Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not affect our processing of your personal data for other non-marketing purposes such as providing a product/service to you, warranty registration, product/service experience or other transactions, etc. 

#### Cookies.

In certain applicable circumstances, you may set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. 

#### Change of Purpose.

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us. 

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so. Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law. 

### 5\. Disclosures of your Personal Data

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above. 

  * Other companies in the Solera Group.
  * Service providers acting as processors who provide IT and system administration services.
  * Professional advisers, acting as processors or joint controllers, including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services. 
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice. 

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions. 

### 6\. International Transfers

Personal data is processed in the United States of America. 

### 7\. Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. 

### 8\. Data Retention

#### How Long Will You Use My Personal Data?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. 

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting us. More specifically, and without limiting the generality of the foregoing, by law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for at least 5 years after they cease being customers for tax, financial auditing, and record keeping purposes. 

In some applicable circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you. 

### 9\. Your Legal Rights

Under certain circumstances, you may have rights under data protection laws to: 

  * **Access** to your personal data. You can access your information online by looking at your account.
  * **Correct** your personal data. You can change your information by accessing your account.
  * **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. We also remove your name from the membership directly within one (1) week of your cancellation of your membership. 
  * **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms. 
  * **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 
  * **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. 
  * **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent. 

#### No Fee Usually Required.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights) unless your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. 

#### What We May Need From You.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. 

#### Time Limit to Respond. 

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

### 10\. Other Service Information

**Connecting With Members Through Other Services.** We may advertise on other social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, to connect with past and current members. These networks typically provide a mechanism for us to target our members by matching email address, phone number and similar information. No third party is permitted to use our members' information in ANY way other than to help us target our advertisements. For Facebook and Twitter, those services never receive the email or phone number. For Twitter advertisements, we use MailChimp to securely exchange the targeting information. 

**Industry Sponsors.** iATN has industry sponsors that subsidize the network and provide support to members. At no time do we share personal data with these companies without your express consent. 

**Business Sponsor Pages.** Business or Business+ premium members receive a web page on iATN to advertise their services to the public. These members control what information they wish to share although the default web page includes the phone number and street address of the business, if it is represented as doing business with the general public. 

**Member Directory.** Members agree as part of registration to allow display of their full name, company name, position, city, state, and country in our member directory that is viewable to anyone browsing the iATN web site. Members who do not wish to have their information displayed can cancel their iATN membership. The directory will be updated within one week. 

**Interactive Content.** Some personal information is displayed with all Interactive Content created on iATN including but not limited to messages posted to the forums, TechHelp help request system, chat rooms, etc. Do not submit Interactive Content if you do not wish personal information to be displayed. 

**Private Email from Members:** iATN does not reveal your email address to other members. Your email address may be visible with Interactive Content you submitted on the network. We also enable communication with you through the use of a form on our website but this does not display your email address.
